谁是小不点儿
Who the winny-binny boy?
你是小小的小不点儿啊
You the winny-winny-binny-binny boy!
别哭啊
Don't cry.
他为什么还在哭
Why is he still crying?
我来抱他一下
Let me hold him for a sec.
来  爸爸抱
Here we go.
不哭了
There we are.
可能他不喜欢我
Maybe it's me.
别傻了  本爱你  他只是爱闹脾气而已
Don't be silly. Ben loves you. He's just being Mr. Cranky Pants.
我跟一个爱闹脾气的约过会
You know, I once dated a Miss Cranky Pants.
很可爱  有点情绪化
Lovely girl. Kinda of moody.
好了  好多了
There we go, all better.
这才是小乖乖
There's my little boy.
我可以试试吗
Can I see something?
厉害
Cool!
他讨厌我  我的侄子还讨厌我
He hates me. My nephew hates me!
好啦  别这么想
Stop. Don't do this.
要是我自己孩子也讨厌我呢  到时怎么办
What if my own baby hates me? What am I gonna do then?
摩妮卡  别说了  太不着边际了
Monica, stop! This is nuts.
你知道要过多久才会遇到这个问题吗
Do you know how long it's gonna be before you actually have to deal with this problem?
你现在连男友都还没
You don't even have a boyfriend yet.
乔伊  她看起来不胖
Joey, she does not look fat.
-拿去  -莫妮卡
- Here you go. - Hey, Mon.
咯咯咯
Goo, goo, goo!
真好笑  我来试试
That is so funny! Let me see that a sec.
-你还好吧  罗斯  -不知道
- You okay, Ross? - I don't know.
这派用的什么原料
What's in this pie?
记不清了  奶油  鸡蛋  面粉  莱姆  奇异果
I don't know. Butter and eggs and flour and lime and kiwi
奇异果  奇异果
Kiwi? Kiwi?!
你之前说这是青柠派
You said it was a key lime pie.
不是  我说的是奇异果派  那样味道才特别
No, I didn't. I said kiwi lime. That's what makes it so special.
那样才会置我于死地
That's what's gonna kill me.
我对奇异果过敏
I'm allergic to kiwi.
你才不会呢  你会过敏的是龙虾  花生跟...
No, you're not. You're allergic to lobster and peanuts and
天啊
Oh, my God!
越来越严重了
It's definitely getting worse.
你的舌头肿了吗
Is your tongue swelling up?
难不成是我的嘴小了
Either that or my mouth is getting smaller!
好  穿上外套  我们去医院
All right. Get your coat. We're going to the hospital.
-他不会有事吧  -不会  打一针就好了
- Is he gonna be ok? - Yeah, he's just gotta get a shot.
其实我觉得好多了  真的
You know, actually, it's getting better. It is. It is.
别去了  谁要玩拼字游戏
Let's not go. Anyone up for Scrabble?
去穿外套
Jacket, now!
但是本怎么办   我们可不能带孩子上医院
What about Ben? We can't bring a baby to the hospital.
交给我们吧
We'll watch him.
够呛
I don't think so.
怎么了  我有七个天主教姐妹
What? I have seven Catholic sisters.
我照顾过上百个小孩
I've taken care of hundreds of kids.
别这样  我们想帮忙  对不对
Come on, we want to do it. Don't we?
拜托  我本来想去打篮球的
I was going to play basketball...
不过球被丢出窗外了
... but I guess that's out the window.
好  如果带他去散步  记得帮他戴帽子  好吗
Okay. If you take him out for a walk, remember to bring his hat,okay?
冰箱里还有一些牛奶  尿布在袋子里
There's milk in the refrigerator and diapers in the bag.
帽子  牛奶
Hat, milk....
懂了
Got it!
包在我们身上
Consider it done!
你听得懂吗
You understood that?
懂啊  我沙叔叔就有大舌头
My uncle Sal has a really big tongue.
是老婆很漂亮的那个吗
Is he the one with the beautiful wife?
瑞秋  想听我今天下午要唱的新歌吗
Hey Rach, wanna hear the new song I'm thinkin' of singing this afternoon?
-今天早上洗澡的时候写的  -好
- I wrote it this morning in the shower. - Okay.
*我一边洗澡  一边在写歌*
*I'm in the shower and I'm writing a song*
*听过的话  请阻止我*
*Stop me if you've heard it*
*我全身泡沫  头发湿搭搭*
*My skin is soapy and my hair is wet*
*海飞丝倒过来  就是丝飞海*
*And Tegrin spelled backward is nirget*
瑞秋  亲爱的  过来一下好吗
Rachel, sweetheart, could I see you for a minute?
什么事
What's up?
告诉你
F.Y.I..
我已经决定聘请一位职业歌手周日下午来演出
I've decided to pay a professional musician to play here on Sundays afternoon.
她叫斯蒂芬妮什么的  应该还不错
Her name is Stephanie something. She's supposed to be very good.
但菲比怎么办
But what about Phoebe?
瑞秋  不是说你朋友表演差
Rachel, it's not that your friend is bad,
是实在太差了
It's that she's so bad...
让我想把手指头穿过眼睛伸进脑袋
...she makes me want to put my finger through my eye into my brain...
然后把它搅成浆糊
...and swirl it around.
那好  你不欣赏她的歌
Okay, so you're not a fan.
可是你不能这样对她
But, I mean, come on. You cannot do this to her.
不不不  你叫我出面
Oh, no no no no. Oh no no no no.I have to do this to her?
*涂皂  冲水  再来*
*Lather, rinse, repeat*
*And lather, rinse, repeat*
*涂皂  冲水  再来*
*洗干净为止*
*As needed*
我觉得我们东西没有带够
You know, I don't think we brought enough stuff.
你是不是忘带宝宝的止痛贴片了
Did you forget to pack the baby's anvil?
我告诉你  这绝对值
I'm telling you, it'll be worth it.
大家都知道女人最爱宝宝了
It's a known fact that women love babies.
女人爱喜欢宝宝的男人  这是感性的问题
Women love guys who love babies. It's the whole sensitive thing.
把他对准那边的宝贝们  说不定会过来一个
Aim him at that pack of babes. Maybe one of them will break away.
不  等一下  她们就算了  正左方来了一个
No. Wait, forget them. We got one. Hard left.
-来  宝宝给我  -不要  我要抱
- Give me the baby. - No, I got him.
快  我说真的
Come on, seriously.
你真的要他吗
Oh, seriously, you want him?
这个小可爱是谁啊
Who is this little cutie-pie?
不是我脸皮厚  但真是...
Well, don't think me immodest, but...
我
... me.
要不要闻闻
Want to smell him?
你现在指的是宝宝吧
I assume we're talking about the baby now.
是呀  他的宝宝味好香  闻闻他的头
Yeah. He's got that great baby smell. Get a whiff of his head.
我想我的子宫震颤了一下
I think my uterus just skipped a beat.
你看吧
What'd I tell you?
你们这样带孩子真好
It's great you're doing this.
我们都是好男人
Well, we are great guys.
我弟弟跟他的男友试了三年都领养不到孩子
My brother and his boyfriend have been trying to adopt for three years.
你们是找哪一家机构
What agency did you two go through?
可这是我的驻点场所
But this is my gig.
这是我的地盘
This is where I play.
我的名字用粉笔写在外面
My name is written out there in chalk.
你不能把粉笔擦掉的
You know, you can't just erase chalk.
对不起  我很遗撼
Honey, I'm sorry.
他居然还要付这个女人酬劳
And he's going to be paying this woman?
那他干脆给她一个宝座  一顶皇冠
Why doesn't he just give her a throne and a crown?
还有一根上面有球的权杖
And, like, a gold stick with a ball on top?
泰利是混蛋  所以我们才常说  泰利是混蛋
Terry is a jerk! That's why we always say, "Terry's a jerk!"
他的外号就是这么来的
That's where that came from.
你说不定已经尽力了
You probably did everything you could.
好吧  我再去试试其它办法
Okay. You know what? Let me just see what else I could do.
听我说  听我说
All right. Look. Look.
要不让她在那个斯蒂芬妮什么的表演完再唱吧
Why don't you just let her go on after Stephanie whatever her name is.
你又不在这里  又不付她钱  没什么损失
You won't be here. You don't pay her.It's not gonna cost you anything.
我不知道
I don't know.
拜托  泰瑞  我帮你洗卡布基诺机好了
Come on, Terry, I'll even clean the cappuccino machine.
你平常不洗卡布基诺机吗
You don't clean the cappuccino machine?
当然洗啊
Of course I clean it.
我是说我会好好洗
I mean, I will clean it.
洗得干干净净
好吧  真是拿你没辙
All right, fine, fine, fine!
-搞定了 -真的
- Done. - Really?
是啊  不看是谁出马了  亲爱的
Yeah. Who's working for you, babe?
天啊  太好了  我能拿多少酬劳
Oh, my God! This is so exciting! How much am I gonna get?
什么
What?
你说他要付钱给演出的人  那...
Well you said that he's paying the people who are playing.
不不  我是说他要付给另一个女人
Oh, no, no no. I meant that he's gonna be paying that other woman
因为她是职业歌手
because she's a professional.
我可不想当唯一免费表演的人
I'm not gonna be the only one who's not getting paid.
-可菲比...  -不行  对不起  不行
- Well, but Pheebs. - No, huh uh, I'm sorry, no.
不  我可不是什么二流的慈善乐队
No, I'm not some sloppy second, you know, charity band.
纽约城里有成千上万个地方
There are thousands of places in this city...
愿意付我出场费
...where people would pay to hear me play.
*我为自己而弹唱*
*When I play, I play for me*
*用不着你的施舍*
*I don't need your charity*
谢谢
Thank you!
我才不要扎针
Well, there's no way I'm gonna get a shot.
他们可以把药水打进我的嘴里
Maybe they can take the needle and squirt it into my mouth.
就像打水枪那样
Like a squirt gun.
你们好  我是卡林医生
Hello there. I'm Dr. Carlin.
我看有人有点过敏反应
I see someone's having a little allergic reaction.
对  医生  我可以单独跟你谈谈吗
Yes. Doctor, can I see you for just a minute please?
我哥有点害怕打针
My brother has a slight phobia about needles.
你有没有告诉他我那个打水枪的主意
Did you tell him about my squirt gun idea?
我的博士哥哥想知道
My brother, the Ph.D., would like to know...
这个针剂有没有办法口服
...if there's any way to treat this orally?
没有  在这种情况之下  打针是难免的
No, under these circumstances it has to be an injection,
而且要马上打针
and it has to be now.
怎么样
So?
好吧  坐下来  医生说这一针非打不可
Ok. Go and have a seat. The doctor says it's got to be a needle.
所以你一定要勇敢起来  就当为我  好吗
You're just going to have to be brave. Can you do that for me?
孩子  你表现得非常好
Oh, boy! You are doing so good.
-要不要握紧我的手  好  -要
- You want to squeeze my hand? Okay. - Yeah.
罗斯  不要握得那么紧
Ross, don't squeeze it so hard.
亲爱的  别握那么紧
Honey, really. Don't squeeze it so hard!
罗斯  放开我的手
Oh, Ross! Let go of my hand!
你的计划真有效  乔伊
That's a good plan, Joe.
下一回想泡妞
Next time we want to pick up women...
我们干脆去公园亲热算了
...we should go to the park and make out.
出租车  出租车
Taxi! Taxi!
你看那票妞儿
Look at that talent.
我在练习拦车  你不错
Just practicing. You're good.
开走吧
Carry on.
等等  等等我们
Wait, wait, wait!
小可爱  他好可爱
Hey, you. He's just adorable.
你能直接告诉他吗  他觉得自己太粉嫩了
Can you tell him that? Because he thinks he looks too pink.
-你们今天出来做什么  -我们没出柜
- What are you guys out doing today? - We're not out.
我们只是帮异性恋朋友
We're two heterosexual guys
带孩子的异性恋男人
hanging with the son of our other heterosexual friend,
做着直男常做的事
doing the usual straight-guy stuff.
讲完了
You done?
我们到站了
There's our stop.
少来了  我们才到了
Get out of here! This is our stop.
你们也住在这附近啊
You guys live around here too?
当然  我们住在那个人行道旁边
Sure. We live in the building by the sidewalk.
你们认识吗
You know it?
对了  既然大家是邻居  一起喝点东西吧
Look. Since we're neighbors, what do you say we get together for a drink?
我们去马可咖啡厅吧
So you want to go to Markel's?
好啊  他们很喜欢我们
Sure, they love us over there.
你们的宝宝呢
Where's your baby?
本  本
Ben! Ben!
很好  他也许能听见你然后按下车铃
That's good. Maybe he'll hear you and pull the cord!
停车  等等  等等  等等
Stop the bus! Wait! Wait! Wait!
你肯定他没有捏断吗  我真的很痛
Are you sure he didn't break it? Because it really hurts.
没有  只有骨挫伤
No, it's just a good bone bruise.
还有这是你戒指造成的刺伤
And right here is the puncture wound from your ring.
-对不起  我真的很抱歉  -没关系
- I'm really sorry. - It's okay.
抱歉
Sorry.
抱歉  我吐字清楚了
Sorry! I got my S's back!
那我们待会儿再庆祝
Which we can celebrate later.
庆祝  庆祝...
Celebrate. Celebrate....
*他是个双  双*
*He was a double, double*
*双关节男孩*
*Double-jointed boy*
你就是那个专业的吉他手吗
So are you the professional guitar player?
对  我叫斯蒂芬妮
Yeah, I'm Stephanie.
对  上面本来有我名字  现在只剩胡萝卜蛋糕了
Right. My name was on there, but now it just says carrot cake.
你会弹几个和弦
So how many chords do you know?
-全都会  -是吗  那你会D调  -会
- All of them. - Oh yeah, so you know D? - Yeah.
-那你会A小调吗  -会
- Do you know A-minor? - Yeah.
你会从D和弦转到A小调吗
Do you know how to go from D to A-minor?
会
Yeah.
那你的吉他有背带吗
So does your guitar have a strap?
-没  -我的有
- No. - Mine does.
*斯蒂芬妮认识所有和弦*
*Stephanie knows all the chords*
快接  快接  快接
Come on! Pick up, pick up!
喂  运输中心吗  对  你好
Hello. Transit Authority? Yes. Hello.
我在帮一本书做调查
I'm doing research for a book.
如果有人把婴儿留在市公车上  该怎么办呢
I was wondering what somebody might do if they left a baby on a city bus.
是  我知道  只有笨蛋才会这么做
Yes, I do realize that would be a stupid character.
是这样  我们今天把汽车安全座椅落在了公交车上
Here's the deal: We lost a car seat on a bus today.
白塑胶材质  有把手  可以用在推车上面
It's white plastic and it fits onto a stroller.
里面还有一个婴儿
And there was a baby in it.
他要跟你讲
He wants to talk to you again.
各位  我们以最热烈的掌声欢迎...
Everybody, let's give a nice warm Central Perk welcome to
*泰利是个混蛋  他不让我工作*
*Terry's a jerk and he won't let me work*
*我恨中央公园咖啡馆*
*And I hate Central Perk*
欢迎斯蒂芬妮·谢弗儿
To Stephanie Schiffer!
首先我想唱一首我为初恋情人写的歌
I'd like to start with a song I wrote for the first man I ever loved.
*柴克力*
*Zachary*
*被请来咬我*
*Are all invited to bite me*
我们打过电话来问公车上的婴儿情况  到了没有
We're the guys that called about the baby! Is he here?!
到了
He's here.
你们之中有一个是父亲吧
I assume one of you is the father.
-是我  -是我
- That's me. - I'm him.
事实上呢  我们两个都是
Actually, we're both the father.
-本  -小家伙
- Oh, Ben! - Hey, buddy.
你知道哪个是本吗
Please tell me you know which one is our baby.
那个T恤上有鸭子  这个有小丑
That one has ducks on his T-shirt and this one has clowns.
本的T恤上绝对是鸭子
And Ben was definitely wearing ducks.
或小丑
Or clowns.
等一下  那个绝对是本
Oh, oh wait. That one's definitely Ben.
记得他嘴边那颗可爱的小痣吗
Remember he had that cute little mole by his mouth!
本  记得我们吗
Hey, Ben! Remember us?
天啊  痣掉了
Okay, the mole came off.
我们该怎么办
What are we gonna do?
丢硬币决定  鸭子或小丑
We'll flip for it. Ducks or clowns.
-硬币赌孩子  -你有更好的主意吗
- Flip for the baby? -You got a better idea?
好吧  赌一把
All right, call it in the air.
正面
Heads.
正面没错
Heads, it is.
我们得确定正面代表什么
We have to assign heads to something!
好的
Right!
鸭子是正面[头]   因为鸭子有头
Ducks is heads because ducks have heads.
哪个没头的小丑跑来给你过过生日
What kind of scary-ass clowns came to your birthday?
*请当我是晨曦中的天使*
*Just call me angel of the morning, angel*
*离开之前  请轻抚我的脸庞*
*Just touch my cheek before you leave me, baby*
*请当我是晨曦中的天使*
*Just call me angel of the morning, angel*
*然后缓缓转身离去*
*Then slowly turn away*
*我不会求你留下*
*I won't beg you to stay*
*陪我*
*With me*
给  我想你可能会冷
Here. I thought you might be cold.
谢谢
Thank you.
看看你  收获真不少
Look at you! You did pretty well.
八块两毛七
$8.27.
其实没那么多  头两块是我放的
But not really, because I put in the first two.
只是让钱滚滚来  还有让自己舒服一点
Just to get the ball rolling and to make myself feel better.
结果呢
Do you?
没有  为钱弹唱这种事太不适合我了
No. You know, this whole playing for money thing is so not good for me.
我不知道  当我唱到  自自自杀
I don't know, when l sang "Su-su-suicide"...
得了一块七毛五
... I got, like, $1.75.
可唱到臭臭猫呢
But then "Smelly Cat"?
别人给了我两毛五跟一个保险套
I got 25 cents and a condom.
所以现在我为臭臭猫感到很难过
So, you know, now I just feel really bad for "Smelly Cat."
我不认为大家都会懂臭臭猫
Honey, I don't think everybody gets "Smelly Cat."
如果你只要养过健康的宠物  那肯定一头雾水
I mean, if all you've ever actually had are healthy pets, then whoosh!
可根本就不是那么回事
But it's not even that, you know?
本来我唱歌只是因为我很高兴
I used to do my songs because it made me happy.
可是现在却全都是为了赚钱
Now it's just all about the money, you know?
菲比  大家都很想你
Well, people missed you in there.
事实上  还有人指名要听臭臭猫呢
In fact, there was actually a request for "Smelly Cat."
真的吗  是谁
Really? From who?
就是我
Well, me.
我知道那不是你最好卖的歌  但我最喜欢那首
And I know it's not your big money song, but it's my favorite.
我是不是不小心丢了一个保险套
Did I accidentally drop a condom in your case?
情况有点紧急
It's kind of an emergency.
-拿去吧  -谢了
- Here you go. - Thanks a lot.
克里斯汀  拿到了
Hey, Christine! I got it!
我想谢谢你今天陪我
I want to thank you for being there for me today.
对不起  我差点捏断你的手
And I'm sorry I almost broke your hand.
没关系  抱歉我对你下了毒
That's okay. I'm sorry I poisoned you.
你还记得我用铅笔戳你的手那回吗
Remember the time I jammed that pencil into your hand?
何止记得   你以为这是什么  雀斑吗
Remember it? What do you think this is, a freckle?
那我用西尔维安的南瓜打你脸那次呢
What about the time I hit you in the face with Sylvian's pumpkin?
天啊  记得我拿扫把插进你自行车轮胎里
Man. Remember when I stuck that broom in your spokes...
结果你翻车头撞到路边那次吗
...and you hit your head on the curb?
不记得了  可我记得别人告诉过我
No. But I remember people telling me about it.
我希望本有个小妹妹
I hope Ben has a little sister.
希望她能够好好整他
And I hope she can kick his ass.
我去拿个新的创可贴
I'm gonna get a new Band-Aid.
我切下你马里布肯娃娃的双腿那次呢
How about the time I cut the legs off your Malibu Ken?
是你干的
That was you?
它的双腿发炎了  不切它会死的
They were infected. He wouldn't have made it.
我的小侄子
My little nephew.
过来  小东西
Come here, little one!
我的小宝贝本
There's my little baby, Ben!
小东西
Hey, my little boy.
他居然没有哭
Hey, he's not crying!
他没哭
太好了
Yes.
派还没吃完
There's still pie!
我来了  我来了
I'm here. I'm here.
我的小宝贝好吗
How's my little boy?
要爸爸帮你换尿布吗   我知道  我知道
You want Daddy to change your diaper? I know, I know.
你今天跟乔伊叔叔和钱德勒叔叔玩得开心吗
Did you have fun with Uncle Joey and Uncle Chandler today?
开心  他今天坐公车了
Yeah. He rode the bus today.
大男孩坐公车
Big boy riding the bus
我有个问题
Hey, I have a question.
他的小屁股上为什么会有服务部财产这些字
How come it says Property of Human Services on his butt?
下面的故事很精彩
You, you are gonna love this.
帮我抱一下本好吗
Can you hold Ben for a sec?
过来  过来
Come here. Come here.
别过来  我手上有奇异果  跑  乔伊  快跑
Stay back! I've got kiwi! Run, Joey, run!
*臭臭猫  臭臭猫*
*Smelly cat, smelly cat*
*他们都喂你吃了什么*
*What are they feeding you*
不对  对不起  是这样的
No, no. I'm sorry, it's:
*臭臭猫  臭臭猫*
*Smelly cat, smelly cat*
有进步
Better!
好多了  很好
Much better. Good.
别难过  这首歌本来就很难
Don't feel bad, because it's a hard song.
-要不要再试一次   -好  从头开始吗
- You want to try it again? - Yeah. From the top?
这首歌没有头  好吗
There is no "top", all right?
这就是臭臭猫的美妙之处
That's the beauty of "Smelly Cat."
-你跟着我唱好了  -好
- Why don't you just follow me. - Okay.
*臭臭猫  臭臭猫*
*Smelly cat, smelly cat*
*他们都喂你吃了什么  *
*What are they feeding you*
*臭臭猫  臭臭猫*
*Smelly cat, smelly cat*
*错不在你*
*It's not your fault*
太过了  对不起
That's too much. Sorry.